<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>triton on Lei.Chat()</title>
    <link>https://www.lei.chat/series/triton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in triton on Lei.Chat()</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - 2026 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lei.chat/&#34;&gt;Lei Zhang&lt;/a&gt;
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:09:38 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.lei.chat/series/triton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Triton Linear Layout: Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.lei.chat/posts/triton-linear-layout-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:09:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lei.chat/posts/triton-linear-layout-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../triton-linear-layout-concept/&#34;&gt;The previous blog post&lt;/a&gt; talked about Triton linear layout concepts, aiming to provide
some underlying motivations and an intuitive understanding.
As a companion, in this one I&amp;rsquo;d like to touch on linear layout internals and follow up with some
concrete examples to show its usage in action and make it even more comprehensible.
Following the same vein, common languages and explanations are preferred instead of mathematical
terms and interpretations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triton Linear Layout: Concept</title>
      <link>https://www.lei.chat/posts/triton-linear-layout-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 14:21:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lei.chat/posts/triton-linear-layout-concept/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Layout is a core concept in Triton for representing and optimizing distribution
mappings from source problems to the target hardware compute and memory
hierarchy.
In this blog post I will talk about linear layout in Triton, the new unifying
mechanism over existing bespoke layouts for different purposes.
The aim is to provide motivation and an intuitive understanding of linear
layout;
I will rely on examples and illustrations instead of theories and proofs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triton Compiler Development Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.lei.chat/posts/triton-compiler-development-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:13:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lei.chat/posts/triton-compiler-development-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://triton-lang.org/&#34;&gt;Triton&lt;/a&gt; provides an elegant solution to program GPU kernels in Python,
positioning itself as a critical component in the modern AI software stack.
To deliver performance and portability, it leverages a compiler, the capability
of which determines the potential.
Hacking the compiler internals is not a simple task.
Here are some tips hopefully useful to folks.
I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep this blog post updated periodically.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
